<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Mijian Xu</title>
    <link>https://xumi1993.github.io/home/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Mijian Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 21:49:32 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xumi1993.github.io/home/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mantle Transition Zone Structure in SE Tibet</title>
      <link>https://xumi1993.github.io/home/project/se-tibet-mtz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 21:49:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xumi1993.github.io/home/project/se-tibet-mtz/</guid>
      <description>The subduction of the Indian Plate beneath SE Tibet and its related volcanism in Tengchong are important geologic processes that accompany the evolution of the Tibetan Plateau. However, it is still not clear whether the subduction and volcanism are confined to the upper mantle or if they extend deep into the mantle transition zone (MTZ). Here, we imaged MTZ structures by using receiver function methods with the waveforms recorded by more than 300 temporary stations in SE Tibet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SplitRFLab</title>
      <link>https://xumi1993.github.io/home/project/splitrflab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 22:33:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xumi1993.github.io/home/project/splitrflab/</guid>
      <description>We add new modules for receiver function (RF) analysis in SplitLab toolbox, which includes the manual RF analysis module, automatic RF analysis and related quality control modules, and H-k stacking module. The updated toolbox (named SplitRFLab toolbox), espe- cially its automatic RF analysis module, could calculate the RFs quickly and efficiently, which is very useful in RF analysis with huge amount of seismic data. China is now conducting the ChinArray project that plans to deploy thousands of portable stations across Chinese mainland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crustal Structure in SE Tibet</title>
      <link>https://xumi1993.github.io/home/project/se-tibet-crust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 22:24:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xumi1993.github.io/home/project/se-tibet-crust/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>